AJAY KUMAR SINGH

General Manager

Address- Faridabad, Haryana Phone- +91 8178776480 E-Mail- Singhak hrj@rediffmail.com

Professional Summary

A go-getter Motivated, Goal oriented and Customer-focused team player who is ready to bring 22 years of sales experience to help a growing company take things to the next level. Looking to apply proven skills in time management, problem-solving and team motivation to successfully lead teams and reached departmental goals with plenty of travel in order to increase company reach and territories. Willing to learn management industry standards while providing exceptional leadership that promotes productivity and professional developments.

Work History

Aug 2020 - Jan 2023

General Manager- Sales & Marketing

Sintex BAPL Limited - India

- Handling pan India business for Plastic sections and factory made doors
- Handling Plastic business (Water Tanks) for West Zone and playing lead role in regaining of brand position, Market share & revival of business network across Zone.
- Strategize for the achievement of regional sales target through the zonal team by break down of annual targets to half yearly then quarterly and finally monthly
- Continuously monitoring the achievement of targets by keeping close check on monthly
- Target achievement by regional manager, area manager and their respective team
- Ensure satisfactory resolution of client queries and concerns in timely manner
- Communicate schemes and offers to the regional managers and ensures their implementation
- Coordinates with marketing for the organization of seminars, meets and conferences on zonal
- Interacts with large customers for the product feedback
- Enhance productivity
- Ensure successful launch of new product
- Coordination with NSM / HO deliver effective communication in co workers
- Planning and structuring the business and team
- Increase the morale of people to take new responsibilities and develop new mangers in team

March 2019 - June 2020

General Manager- Sales & Marketing

Vectus Industries Limited, Rajasthan & Gujarat

 A premium Tank manufacturing company along with Pipes , Fittings and Moldings products, Established tanks and pipe business across Gujarat & Rajasthan market, spreading the brand across the region, handling business of 110 Cr Annually. July 2017 - Feb 2019

Dy. General Manager- Sales

Acrysil Limited-Sternhagen (Premium Tiles & S.W) - North & East India

- Worked as a DGM-Sales and Marketing for North & East India.
- Established a high end premium luxury bathroom concepts brands which includes of sanitary, tiles & wellness products for high end premium customers in north and eastern region & take it to a level of 50 Cr. in a span of 2 years.
- Manager and selling the product through dealer, architect and builders in Delhi and N.C.R during the course of time in job in the same organization elevated up to Sr Manager.

Jan 2011 - June 2017

Zonal Manager- Sales

Roca Bathroom Products Pvt. Ltd - North India

- Joined organization as Area Head-(Delhi–NCR) in Jan 11 and reached up to level of Zonal Manager handling Northern India operations with a CAGR of 12%.
- Got three promotions and best sales manager award consistently for three years.

June 2006 - Jan 2011

Sr. Manager- Sales

Kajaria Ceramics LTD. - Delhi-NCR & Haryana, India

 Joined the company as Dy. Manager and selling the products through dealer, architect and builders in Delhi and NCR during the course of time in job in the same organization elevated up to Sr. Manager.

Sept 2000 - June 2005

Assistant Manager- Sales

H&R Johnson (I) Limited-Haryana

- Joined as a service engineer and promoted in sales in a span of 6 months.
- Got two promotions and reached up to a level of Asst. Manager –Sales.
- Looking after channel /Institutional/Key accounts sales of Haryana region.

Education

July 1994 - June 1995

AISSCE

Kendriya Vidyalaya, New Delhi

July 1996 - July 1999

Diploma in Civil Engineering

Pusa Polytechnic New Delhi

July 2004 - July 2006

P G Diploma: Business Management

Bhartiya Vidyapeeth, Delhi

Personal Details

Date of Birth Marital Status Languages Known 25th Dec, 1977 Married English, Hindi

Sign: